Guide to the Papers of Alice Virginia Keliher 1918-1995 MC 139
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Personal Memorabilia
  - Audio tape: Day in the life of teacher student reports used in article, "Mental Hygiene"; July, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058117 8
  - Audio tape: Music. University of Utah; Summer, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Audio tape: Music of Hawaii; Summer, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Audio tape: Story of Citizens, Commission on Children;Dec. 9, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Audio tape: Keliher on Dewey. Final Session Hawaii Workshop, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Audio tape: NYU-125 A. 1st Committee Meeting, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Audio tape: 5th Year comm.; 25-May-53, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Audio tape: 5th Year comm.; 25-May-53, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Audio tape: NYU Fifth Year Program. Report by June Mc Leod, 125 A; 12-May-53, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Audio tape: Wheelock. 8 Week Session Head Start; 21-Apr-53, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Audio tape: Carol Smith to 45" on 600 school. 6th Year Seminar; 17-Feb-53, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Audiotape: AVK on World Conditions Refugees. Chinese student. N Y State Welfare Conference. AVK talks and excerpts, 1952, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Audio tape: NEA Regional con. Minneapolis; 12-Apr-54, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Audiotape: Fulton Co. speech: Child Behavior and AVK on pilgrimage W A B C; February 24, 1954;December 26, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Audio tape: Fulton Co. Atlanta, 2nd half speech and End Fulton County (10 min.); 24-Feb-54, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Audio tape: Atlanta ACEI, incomplete; 22-Feb-54, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Audio tape: M. Asher-1st year teachers. What I Wish I Had Known in Sept. and L A County AVK comment, 1953, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Audio tape: 1-NEA Regional. Impact of Times on Children; 12-Apr-54, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Audio tape: Kent State Reading Conference and Dr. Sheldon comments; July, 1955, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Audio tape: Kent State, ibid, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Audio tape: Enriched Learning Experiences, Burbank, C A; 29-Nov-55, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Audio tape: Lawrence K. Frank. Human Aspirations. and AVK. NYU class; August 7,1952, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Audio tape: Michigan ASCD. Who is Asking the Questions?; Dec., 1957, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Audio tape: Keliher-Jacobs on Creativity and Dramatics and End of N E A Regional Conference and interview. Portland, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Audio tape: NEA Portland, Radio broadcast; Feb., 1958, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Audio tape: Athens, G A. 1 Mental Hygiene Meeting; 25-Jun-59, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Audio tape: LASCK-Berkeley CA; Dec. 2, 1960, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Audio tape: Kilpatrick on Dewey;14-Nov-59, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Audio tape: Wayne-Talk on Learning that Lasts. AVK 50th birthday--NYU and Hawaii students; July 13, 1960; Jan., 1953 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Audio tape: E C E C at Mills College, N Y. Speech recordings; May, 1962, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Audio tape: A C E I, Study conference. Cleveland "Balanced Program" and E C E C conference; April, 1960; April 21,1961 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Audio tape: Michigan principals;21-Apr-61, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Audio tape: Excerpts, Panel and AVK responses. New Brunswick, NJ and excerpts of Alabama story, "Pep" and measuring cup, 1961, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Audio tape: Roosevelt School, NJ Discussion change from homo to hetero grouping; 27-Feb-62, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Audio tape: Roosevelt 75th Birthday N B C Marion Anderson E T A L. and Wayne, Talk on Learning that Lasts; 13-Jul-60, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Audio tape: Kilpatrick 90th Birthday, Jersey City State College; 11-Apr-62, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Audio tape: Kilpatrick Birthday, Sanders panel, undated (Box 19, Folder 36A)
  - Audio tape: Pasadena, CA. Emo Needs in Changing World; June 1963; 1965 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Audio tape: Montebello, Cultural Influences on Learning and End of Pasadena; June,1963, undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Audio tape: Today's Changing Cultures, South Bend; 27-Aug-63, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Audio tape: The Reluctant Reader. Richmond, VA; 22-Mar-63, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Audio tape: ACEI National Meeting/Portland. Keynote Address: To Study Groups and "Reaching the Individual as a Person", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Audio tape: Interview, Mother Talented Adolescent. Pullman, W A; 27-Jul-64, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Audio tape: Wheelock College. Founders Day, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Audio tape: Minneapolis. Kay Neville's staff and "Environment for Learning"; 20-Apr-65, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Audio tape: Creativity. Minneapolis.; April, 1965, undated (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Audio tape: Arizona State University. Tempe Keynote--Head Start training plus student report--8 week program, Wheelock; Summer, 1966, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Audio tape: Graduation address. Patterson, N J. State College and Portland principals; June 8, 1960;November 16, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Audio tape: Portland principals; 16-Nov-66, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Audio tape: Portland principals--ACEI; 16-Nov-66, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Audio tape: Portland principals--Talk to board members. ACEI Portland, Teacher Education National Meeting; November 16, 1966; 1964 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Audio tape: NEA Dept. EI principals. Boston and directions in Early Childhood Education; 10-Apr-67, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Audio tape: De Kalb--University of Illinois. Speech in Children Development Discussion; 18-Jun-68, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Audio tape: De Kalb--University of Illinois, undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Audio tape: North Carolina, KGN. Assoc.; 25-Oct-68, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Audio tape: AVK interpretive summary, Olson meeting NYU; April 2, 1960; October 25, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Audio tape: Kindergarten conference U. Mass Amherst; 7-Mar-69, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Audio tape: U. of Maine-Farmington student planned conference;10-Oct-70, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Audio tape: On structure, Tucson, TAYCE; February 24,1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Audio tape: Tucson, TAYCE; 23-Feb-71, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Audio tape: Ibid. and Burbank; 29-Nov-55, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Audio tape: Child Development and Learning, AVK, undated (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Audio tape: ACE group Dallas. Reminiscences Austin, workshop; December 8., 1972; June,1962 (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Audio tape: NAEYC--infants, Seattle. Keliher on Dewey, End Hawaii talk, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Audio tape: U. of Arizona seminar, Herb Wilson; November, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Audio tape: San Antonio AVK, Energy Saving Today, Children's Initiative. And SAAEYC curr. workshop, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Audio tape: Child Care Information Center and vital issues in early childhood education Part I, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - Audio tape: Vital issues in early childhood ed. Part II., undated (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Audio tape: Dr. Anthony on Piaget NAEYC Dallas; Nov. 1975, undated (Box 19, Folder 68. A)
  - Audio tape: Ibid and Trud et al, undated (Box 19, Folder 68. B)
  - Audio tape: Jordan and Caldwell, undated (Box 19, Folder 68. C)
  - Audio tape: Fenner Wheelock College; February, 1965, undated (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Audio tape: Engleman on TV, CBS, Betty Caldwell. 21st century and Fred Rawbinger farewell to AVK; 11-May-64, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Audio tape: Millay-5" Keliher readings Millay. Edna St.Vincent Millay by Dorothy Stickney. "A Lovely Light"; 22-Apr-62, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - Audio tape: Mrs. Harris Thanksgiving, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 72)
  - Audio tape: N.E.A. E/K/N/E Alice Keliher "Enhancing the Child's Feeling of Safe.", undated (Box 19, Folder 73)
  - Audio tape: Univ. of Maryland excerpts, Gantt Introduction. AVK: "Who Speaks for our Children", 1973 (Box 19, Folder 74)
  - Audio tape: Wilson-Keliher. A C E I archives. Confidential to Velma; December 16, 1976; January 29, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 75)
  - Audio tape: Dr. Edward Zigler "Head-Start: Not a Program But An Evolving Concept" Dallas, Texas; November, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 76)
  - Audio tape: Harold Hine--On Vietnamese Children Dallas, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 77)
  - Audio tape: Hughes; 20-Feb-70, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 78)
  - Audio tape: Ibid, undated (Box 19, Folder 79)
  - Audio tape: Eleanor Roosevelt; 2-Jul-59, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 80)
  - Audiotape: E. Roosevelt--Peter and the Wolf, Boston Symphony, Kouvensvistsky, conductor, undated (Box 19, Folder 81)
  - Audio tape: E. Roosevelt-Vassar College. AVK speech, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 82)
  - Audio tape: E. Roosevelt-Vassar, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 83)
  - Audio tape: Bess Haskell, undated (Box 19, Folder 84)
  - Audio tape: Bess and Henry Haskell. City's country curriculum and camp, undated (Box 19, Folder 85)
  - Audio tape: Ibid, Feb.,1977, undated (Box 19, Folder 86)
  - Audio tape: Bea Lamm on Mary Fisher;March, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 87)
  - Audio tape: The World Situation. Kilpatrick, Hushih, R. Bunche, undated (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Audio tape: Civilization and the Good Life. Kilpatrick, Axtelle, Childs, Lindeman and Personal Characteristics necessary to civilization and the good life. Kilpatrick, Anderson, Brameld, Melby, Overstreet, Roup, Taylor, undated (Box 19, Folder 89)
  - Audio tape: Civilization and the Good Life. Kilpatrick and children, undated (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Audio tape: Kilpatrick, Beck, Brooks, Gans, Melby, Trudaweil, undated (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - Audio tape: New Years Eve. Hawaii Students, Melbys messages home and Keliher--Teen Age Mothers WSCV, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Audio tape: Gesell, Arnold L. Child Development and a Science of Man and Anna Freud, On Aggression, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 93)
  - Audio tape: John Meier. Innovations in Early Childhood Programs, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 94)
  - Audio tape: Alice Yardley, Structuring the Learning Situation and Sarah Hammond Leeper, A C E I keynote, Salt Lake City. Hymes-Dittman parent Ed Over the Years, and Taylor Hymes--Parent Coup Nursery Schools, 1975, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 95)
  - Audio tape: Mark; Feb-May 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 97)
  - Audio tape: Brazelton and Provence, undated (Box 19, Folder 98)
  - Audio tape: Child Development and Learning. Dr. Samuel Braun; Summer seminar, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 99)
  - Audio tape: Play Mrs. Docia Zavitkousky, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 100)
  - Audio tape: Language,Intellectual and Cognitive Abilities, Dr. Bruce Gardner, undated (Box 19, Folder 101)
  - Audio tape: Comparative Programs, Dr. Edith Dowley, undated (Box 19, Folder 102)
  - Audio tape: Keliher on High Schools, WSCV; 27-Jul-71, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 103)
  - Audio tape: WSCV, AVK "Parents Enjoy Children" and "Babies and Toys"; 27-Jun-72, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 104)
  - Audio tape: WSVC, Acoma Indians; Aug 15-17, undated (Box 19, Folder 105)
  - Audio tape: WSCV; 20-Jun-74, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 106)
  - Audio tape: Guam Report, undated (Box 19, Folder 107 A)
  - Audio tape: Guam Report, undated (Box 19, Folder 107 B)
  - Audio tape: Guam Report, undated (Box 19, Folder 107 C)
  - Audio tape: Mrs. Roosevelt NYU and Yale seminars; 8-May-54, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 108 A)
  - Audio tape: 2 Liese; 4-Apr-72, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 108 B)
  - Audio tape: 4 Liese and Isobel, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 108 C)
  - Audio tape: Bureau Indian Affairs and BIA Kinder Conference, Albuquerque; 7-Mar-68, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 109)
  - Audio tape: Looking Back and Where Are You Going Marian Edelman, undated (Box 19, Folder 110)
  - Audio tape: ACEI Conference, Keynote General Session, Jacobs, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 111)
  - Audiotape: University of Maryland and talk, and AVK "Who Speaks for the Children?"; May, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 112)
  - Audio tape: L. Jacobs and "My Last NYU Class"; 26-Jul-60, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - Audio tape: Hymes--NYU; 19-Jul-60, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - Audio tape: Mrs. Roosevelt and Mrs. Vining, undated (Box 19, Folder 115 A)
  - Audio tape: Rock Chisolm, ACEI, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 115 B)
  - Audio tape: Lawrence Frank, 75th Birthday, G. Murphy, M. Mead, AVK, Blos; 5-Jan-66, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 116)
  - Audio tape: Pam; 30-Sep-77, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 117 A)
  - Audio tape: AVK interview, undated (Box 19, Folder 117 B)
  - Audio tape: Shaftel-On Basics; 27-Apr-75, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 118)
  - Audio tape: Discussion on Kilpatrick, Georgia College, undated (Box 19, Folder 119 A)
  - Audio tape: Kilpatrick at Georgia College, undated (Box 19, Folder 119B)
  - Audio tape: Zirbes; May, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 120)
  - Audio tape: Developmental Vision Dr. Herman H. Auerback and Dr. John D. Renyo; Summer seminar, 1971, undated (Box 19, Folder 121)
  - Audio tape: Infant Development Dr. Frances Horowitz, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 122)
  - Audio tape: Parent Involvement Mrs. Bess V. Atwell, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 123)
  - Audio tape: Summary Symposium, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 124)
  - Audio tape: Dr. Gerald Looney, Television and Children, undated (Box 19, Folder 125)
  - Audio tape: R.T.O. conference Engleman-Biber, undated (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Audio tape: Jacobs by F. Shipley; 1-Jan-79, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 127)
  - Audio tape: Pace--Talk to staff and Parents--Barton School, Tucson; 13-Mar-79, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 128)
  - Audio tape: Alice Keliher on W. H. Kilpatrick, University of Georgia seminar; 4-May-83, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Audio tape: Alice Keliher on W. H. Kilpatrick, University of Georgia seminar; 5- Apr-83, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Audio tape: Edna St. Vincent Millay Part Renaissance Sonnets, undated (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Audio tape: A Recorded Portrait: Eleanor Roosevelt, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - Audio tape: 100th Birthday celebration, Dr. Anderson on Eleanor Roosevelt, Mrs. Louis, Mrs. Rose, and Mrs. Keliher; 10-Oct-84, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Audio tape: Chicago PCC, undated (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - Audio tape: Chicago PCC; 22- May-67, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 135)
  - Slides: Guam Headstart, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058118 6
  - Slides: India Children Misc., undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Slides: Peterborough, Acoma, David and Pam's wedding, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Slides: Migrants--Tucson U.S. Phoenix Day, Cape, Hampton, Smith, England, De Grazia--Copper Mines, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Slides: Joshua Tree, San Francisco, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Slides: Arizona People, De Grazia, Mexico, Hermosilla, Guaymas, Athens, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Slides and Photos: Peterborough, Sea Island, Marblehead, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058119 4
  - Slides and Photos: General Travel, England to Peterborough, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Slides and Photos: Universal Child I, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Slides and Photos: Acoma, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Slides and Photos: Misc. Arizona, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Slides and Photos: Universal Child II, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Slides and Photos: Sedona, Salome, Muir Woods, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Slides and Photos: Guam, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Slides and Photos: Arizona, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Slides and Photos: Richie Picnic, Kilpatrick Tumb, etc., undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Slides and Photos: India clippings, India, Ireland, Guam, Belgium, California photos, negatives, and postcards, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Slides and Photos: Personal photos, friends, and family, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)